Hello Hello
Everyone Welcome to my YouTube channel
Keypad Sample In today's video we
will talk about ICICI Lombard General
Insurance who declared
their third quarter results on the nineteenth century of Kalyani
and due to higher plane
rates the join numbers have
missed the analyst expectations
so in this video we will discuss their numbers
in detail and will also talk about
whether you should buy ICICI Lombard's stock at the current price or
not and
before moving forward if you have not yet subscribed to the channel then
please
motivate us by subscribing so first of all
if we will talk about what does
not work then ICICI Lombard
General Insurance is a leading private
sector general insurance company of India
and you
can see their different products that they provide all types of general insurance and
non-life insurance
and if we look at their product mix then the
largest share is of their motor
insurance in which motor on the match and
motor third party insurance
constitutes about 44% of their overall product
and health  Travel and personal accident
insurance is their twenty-two percent and
after this comes their fire insurance
because it is about 17 percent, so this is their main
insurance and if we
look at the shareholding pattern of the company, then 48.05
percent share is with their promoter i.e. this
bank and around eight percent is with
foreign institutional investors
including thirteen percent is with domestic
institutional and around ten percent is
with retail shareholders
and if we talk about the third quarter functions of the company, then
due to increase in underwriting charges, the
third quarter profit of Lombard General Insurance has been
less than the analyst expectations. Analysts were expecting
that their third quarter profit could be 402
point five crores, whereas
in actual it was 307 point five crores and if
compared to the previous quarter, then it
is 29 percent less. In the previous quarter,
they had a profit of around 447 crores
and  If we compare these quarters with last year, then
their profit has increased by 1.27 percent from there.
Last year, in the same quarter
ended December 2020, they had a
profit of around Rs 334 crore and
if we look at the performance of the first ninth of the
period from April to December, then
their profit after tax in the ninth has been Rs
959 crore, whereas compared to last year,
it has decreased by a quarter percent as compared to the first ninth of last year and
if we talk about the reason for the decrease in their profit, then the
reason for that is the
increase in their combined dues. What is combined dues,
it comes that the claims
they paid and apart from that, whatever
management expenses there were,
how much were the premiums received in comparison to that, so last year in their third
quarter, the combined thresher was 98%, which has
now increased to 105 percent. You
can see here that the premium they earned on
net basis on this was Rs 30830
crore, which was Rs 10830 crore in the last
Although there was an increase of 2% compared to the previous quarter, but the
expenses were
3581 crores, which means that overall they had an
underwriting launch of 269 crores, due to which
their overall profit is less and the
reason being given for this is
that the company has merged with Bharti AXA
and the expense ratio of Bharti AXA is also on the
side, due to that their
other expenses have also increased,
if we talk about revenue, it is
one percent more, it is 3854 crores,
which was 3828 crores in the previous quarter
and if we talk about the share, then it is
60.47 crores, whereas in the previous quarter it
was 9.11 rupees, although the Bloomberg
estimates had pegged the share at 3.69 and
if we talk about the solvency ratio of the company, then
it is 2.45 now, which was
2.49 in the previous quarter.  It should also be noted that whatever the
minimum regulatory requirement is, it is
still quite good from there
and if we talk about the cement
price performance of the company, then the biggest setback that the
company has faced as compared to the previous quarter is
in their motor insurance act. In the last quarter, they had a
profit of ₹330 crores, which has come down to ₹28.90 crores this
time.
Although there is a profit, it
is much less than the previous quarter
and the reason for this is being told that the
third party premium has not been revised for the last two years.
Apart from this, if we
talk about their motor on damage portfolio, then the
number of clans there is big
and apart from this,
they are constantly under pressure due to the underwriting margin because new
players are coming in this segment who are
offering a competitive price to
increase their market share, due to which
their margins have been affected.
After this, if we talk about their second segment, health
segment, then their loss there, be it
health or retail segment,
It was 19.4 crores last time
which has increased to 20.3 crores, which means that the
commitment is incurring a loss. If we
talk about the corporate and government business help segment, then there has been an
increase in their profits and it is
not less that if they are
compared with the second stupid but, then
they have made 114 profits from there and the cost of
treatment is also less due to the
infection reminder on the Corbett infection.
Anna's company has
said that the treatment of other people is being done
by some hospitals, then there is a
condition for that only. Apart from this,
if we talk about other segments, whether it is
crop insurance, fire insurance,
marine insurance or their miscellaneous
and products,
there has been an increase in profit in general insurance
and if it will be discussed whether
we should buy the shares of Allahabad at the current price, then
first of all, if you look at the performance of their shares, then
in 3 years
they have given a good
return of 65 percent.  It is very disappointing that for the last one year
their returns have been negative by about 6%
and in the last 3 months also
their stock has fallen by around 7%. It is understood that
in the last one month
they have shown some recovery and their
stock has fallen by five times. It is understood that
yesterday also either in anticipation of the results or the
shares of all the insurance companies were under pressure yesterday, then
their stock had fallen by 1.7%.
It is understood that Kalyani Securities has
given a target price of celery of 1520 before the results are out from them and
if we make a paste of your ticket app and
see it, then according to them their average
price is
107 and on the right side it is 108 and
on the lower left side it is more than 100. Yesterday's closing was
at 1823. So according to that their
current price
is much below the average target price there
but the pricing looks attractive and
if we look at the fundamentals behind it then it is
100  It is a large-
cap company with a market capitalization of crores and its PRS, but if we look at it, the
valuation is back because its shares have
not performed in the last one year. With
all their love for the insurance sector,
specifically in the private sector,
their PRS looks quite attractive.
Apart from this, the return on equity
of the company is decent, it is more than 20%, so the
owner company seems good. It is
under a little pressure because due to Kuber, the
claims are a little big and there is a
little pressure being
seen in its motor segment. But its pricing
seems attractive. So I feel
that if some correction is seen in it
due to today's results, then there could be a good opportunity to
buy it for the long term.
In the coming time, it can give you a return of 35 percent
in a year from now.
Before launching the video, as
always, I will give a disclaimer that if you
want to invest in this company, then
talk to your partner and then
invest in it only if you feel comfortable. Thank you.  So much for watching the
video and audio all